<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>io.github.hydrusnetwork.hydrus</id>
  <name>Hydrus</name>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.hydrusnetwork.hydrus.desktop</launchable>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>WTFPL</project_license>
  <developer id="io.github.hydrusnetwork">
    <name>Hydrus Network</name>
  </developer>
  <summary>Organize media on the desktop</summary>
  <description>
    <p>The hydrus network client is a desktop application written for Anonymous and other internet enthusiasts with large media collections. It organises your files into an internal database and browses them with tags instead of folders, a little like a booru on your desktop. Tags and files can be anonymously shared through custom servers that any user may run. Everything is free, nothing phones home, and the source code is included with the release. It is developed mostly for Windows, but builds for Linux and macOS are available (perhaps with some limitations, depending on your situation).</p>
    <p>Currently importable filetypes are:</p>
    <ul>
        <li>images - jpg, gif (including animated), png (including animated!), tiff, webp, bmp</li>
        <li>video - webm, mp4, mpeg, avi, mov, mkv, flv, wmv</li>
        <li>audio - mp3, flac, ogg, wma</li>
        <li>misc - swf, pdf, psd, zip, rar, 7z</li>
    </ul>
    <p>The client can download files and parse tags from a number of websites, including by default:</p>
    <ul>
        <li>various imageboards, with a thread watcher</li>
        <li>the popular boorus</li>
        <li>gallery sites like deviant art, and pixiv</li>
        <li>tumblr and twitter</li>
    </ul>
    <p>And can be extended to download from more locations using easily shareable user-made downloaders. It can also be set to 'subscribe' to any gallery search, repeating it every few days to keep up with new results.</p>
    <p>The program's emphasis is on your freedom. There is no DRM, no spying, no censorship. The program never phones home.</p>
  </description>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_general_search.png</image>
      <caption>A simple tag search</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_desu.png</image>
      <caption>Media viewer</caption>
    </screenshot>
   <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_thread_watcher.png</image>
      <caption>The thread watcher works for 4chan and 8chan</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_deviant_art.png</image>
      <caption>Gallery downloader</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_big_search.png</image>
      <caption>Display and manage thousands of files</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_gunnerkrigg_collect.png</image>
      <caption>Files can be sorted and collected by their tags</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_fullscreen_blame.png</image>
      <caption>Media viewer in fullscreen</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_video.png</image>
      <caption>Many file formats are supported</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/images/screenshot_booru.png</image>
      <caption>You can run your own (simple!) booru</caption>
    </screenshot>
 </screenshots>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/hydrusnetwork/hydrus/issues</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://www.patreon.com/hydrus_dev</url>
  <url type="contact">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/contact.html</url>
  <url type="faq">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/faq.html</url>
  <releases>
    <release version="586" date="2024-08-15">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_586</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 586</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed up a bad preload routine in the new sibling/parents dialogs that was doing busy wait and eating up bunch of extra CPU</li>
          <li>Simplified the main sibling/parent chain-following search</li>
          <li>Further optimised the recursive loop of this search, particularly for parents which has to do some additional sibling ideal lookup stuff to join chains coupled by sibling relations</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="585" date="2024-08-08">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_585</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 585</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The tags->manage tag siblings/parents dialogs now load quickly.</li>
          <li>The main edit operations in this dialog are now 'asynchronous', which means there is actually a short delay between the action firing and the UI updating. most of the time it is so fast it isn't noticeable</li>
          <li>The dialogs now have a sticky workspace 'memory'</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="584" date="2024-07-25">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_584</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 584</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a logical hole in the recent 'is this URL that is saying (deleted/already in db) trustworthy,</li>
          <li>The 'copy all' and paste buttons in the manage known urls dialog are replaced with icon buttons, and the copy button now copies the current selection if there is one</li>
          <li>The newish Regex input widget (the one that goes green/red based on current text validity) now propagates an Enter key into a dialog ok event when appropriate</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="583" date="2024-07-18">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_583</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 583</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added a 'command palette' options page. the ability to show menubar and media actions is now set here with a couple of checkboxes (previously these were hidden behind advanced mode)</li>
          <li>You can also now search for 'page of pages' with the command palette. this is turned on in the same new options page</li>
          <li>The new sidecar test panel now only shows its notebook tabs if there is more than one source. the tab labels, when shown, are now '1st' ... '2nd' ordinal strings respective to the source list on the left</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="582" date="2024-07-11">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_582</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 582</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed an issue where setting a file 'collect' was not automatically sorting the collected objects internally properly</li>
          <li>Fixed a weird internal error state in the import folders manager where it could get confused about and throw an error regarding the import folders' next work times if an internal update notification occured during an import folder working</li>
          <li>Fixed a typo error with the shortcut set 'special duplicate' button</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="581" date="2024-07-05">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_581</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 581</p>
        <ul>
          <li>A new Dark Blue stylesheet is added</li>
          <li>timedelta widgets now enforce their minimum time on focus-out rather than value change</li>
          <li>The filename-import tagging panel no longer emits a slow update signal when typing with an unchecked checkbox</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="580" date="2024-06-27">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_580</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 580</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The taglist right-click menu now has a maintenance->regenerate tag display command</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue where read-only import files would not delete from the temp dir after import</li>
          <li>The new 'eye' icon in the media viewer now has 'apply image ICC Profile colour adjustments'</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="579" date="2024-06-20">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_579</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 579</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Added some new scroll-to tech to my multi-column lists</li>
          <li>Import folders now work in a far more efficient way</li>
          <li>The default bandwidth rules for a hydrus repository are boosted from 512MB a day to 2GB</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="578" date="2024-06-06">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_578</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 578</p>
        <ul>
          <li>We now have animated webp support!</li>
          <li>The five new 'draw hover-window text in the background of media viewer' options are now copied to the media viewer itself, under a new 'eye' icon menu button.</li>
          <li>Added a 'network report mode (silent)' to the help->debug menu, which does everything the network report mode does but with silent logging rather than a million popups. should help with longer-term debugging</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="577" date="2024-05-30">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_577</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 577</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Thanks to a user, we have some new OS-file-explorer integration</li>
          <li>The 'media' shortcut set gets the new 'open file properties' and 'open with...' commands to plug into these new features</li>
          <li>The manage times single-time edit dialog's paste button can now eat any datstring you can think of. try pasting 'yesterday 3am' into it, it'll work!</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="576" date="2024-05-23">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_576</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 576</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The mpv player no longer hangs the UI thread on file load if the file manager is busy. it now just shows a black square until things are freed up. sorry this took so long to fix!</li>
          <li>The client file storage system has a new two-layer locking mechanism that allows for massively more parallel access, even when files are importing. file imports should lag out file/thumbnail load significantly less</li>
          <li>Tthanks to a user, we now have support for legacy Microsoft Office documents (.doc, .ppt, .xls), and a framework for other OLE based documents in future</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="575" date="2024-05-16">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_575</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 575</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The new 'children' tab now sorts its results by count, and it only shows the top n (default 40) results. you can edit the n under options->tags. let me know how this works IRL, as this new count-sorting needs a bit of extra CPU</li>
          <li>When you ask subscriptions to 'check now', either in the 'edit subscription' or 'edit subscriptions' dialogs, if there is a mix of DEAD and ALIVE subs, it now pops up a quick question dialog asking whether you want to check now for all/alive/dead</li>
          <li>Thanks to a user, I think we have fixed ICC profile processing when your system ICC Profile is non-sRGB</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="574" date="2024-05-09">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_574</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 574</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The filetype selector in system:filetype now expands to eat extra vertical space if the dialog is resized</li>
          <li>The filetype selector in file import options is moved a bit and also now expands to eat extra vertical space</li>
          <li>Added a new 'apply image ICC Profile colour adjustments' checkbox to options->media. this simply turns off ICC profile loading and application, for debug purposes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="573" date="2024-05-02">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_573</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 573</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The archive/delete and duplicate filters now yes/no confirm when you say to 'forget' at the end of a filtering run</li>
          <li>The duplicate filter page now only allows you to set the search location to local file domains--so it'll only ever try to search and show pairs for files you actually have</li>
          <li>Refactored some question/button dialog stuff</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="571" date="2024-04-18">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_571</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 571</p>
        <ul>
          <li>When you finish an archive/delete filter and there are several domains you could delete from, the 'commit' buttons are now disabled for 1.2 seconds. this catches you from accidentally spamming enter through a surprise complicated decision</li>
          <li>Under options->files and trash, you can now say 'when finishing filtering, always delete from all possible domains', which makes the above decision always single domain. hit this if you do want to spam through this and are fine always deleting from everywhere</li>
          <li>The client will now, by default, attempt to load truncated images. this was previously off until you set it per-session-on in a debug menu, but is now a checkbox under options->media. some weird damaged jpegs and pngs should now load, fingers crossed</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="570" date="2024-04-11">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_570</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 570</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Wrote a thing to wrap tooltips and applied it everywhere. every tooltip in the program should now wrap to 80 characters</li>
          <li>The thumbnail view is now better about pausing the current video if you open it externally in various ways</li>
          <li>The 'open' submenu you get off of a file right-click is now exactly the same for the thumbnail menu and the media viewer menu, with all commands working in either place, the labels are also brushed up a little</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="568" date="2024-03-28">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_568</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 568</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Thanks to a user, the new docx, pptx, and xlsx support is improved, with better thumbnails</li>
          <li>Thanks to a user, the cbz scanner now ignores the __MACOSX folder</li>
          <li>Thanks to a user, setting the Qt style in options->style should be more reliable (fixing some name case sensitivity issues)</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="566" date="2024-03-14">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_566</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 566</p>
        <ul>
          <li>When you boot a 'manage tags' dialog on multiple files, a new ± button now lets you do 'incremental tagging'. this is where you, let's say for twenty files, tag them from page:1->page:20. this has been a long time in the works, but now we have thumbnail reorganisation tech, it is now sensible to do.</li>
          <li>The dialog lets you set a namespace (or none), start point (e.g. you can start tagging at page:19 if you are doing the second chapter etc...), the step (you can count by +2 every file, instead of +1, or even -1 to decrement), the subtag prefix (so you can say 'page:insert-4' or something), and the subtag suffix (for, say, 'page:2 (wip)')</li>
          <li>The last namespace is remembered between dialog opens, and if the first file in the selection has a number tag in that namespace, that is the number the 'start' will initialise with. a bit of overlap/prep may save time here!</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="565" date="2024-03-07">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_565</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 565</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Options->sort/collect now offers four places to customise default tag sort. instead of having one default sort for everything, there's now sort for search pages, media viewers, and the manage tags dialogs launched off of them</li>
          <li>When you copy namespaces from the tag filter list, it now copies the actual underlying data text like character:, which you can paste in elsewhere, rather than the pretty "character" tags display text</li>
          <li>Brushed up some of the UI and help text on the tag filter UI</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="564" date="2024-02-29">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_564</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 564</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The system predicates for width, height, num_notes, num_words, num_urls, num_frames, duration, and framerate now support two different kinds of approximate equals, ≈: absolute (±x), and percentage (±x%)</li>
          <li>All system:framerate=x searches are now converted to ±5%, which is what they were behind the scenes</li>
          <li>Updated the NumberTest object to hold specific percentage and absolute ± values</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="563" date="2024-02-22">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_563</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 563</p>
        <ul>
          <li>By default, Alt+Home/End/Left/Right now does the new thumbnail rearranging</li>
          <li>The tag service menu button that appears in the autocomplete panel and sometimes some other places in advanced mode now shows a proper check mark in its menu beside its current value</li>
          <li>The location context menu button on the other side of an autocomplete panel and some other places also now shows a check mark in its menu beside its current value</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="562" date="2024-02-15">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_562</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 562</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Page tab drag and drops will now not start unless the click has lasted more than 100ms</li>
          <li>The manage tags dialog now shows the current count of tags for each page tab, and, if there are outstanding changes, shows an asterisk</li>
          <li>The migrate database dialog is renamed move media files</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="561" date="2024-02-08">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_561</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 561</p>
        <ul>
          <li>On the thumbnail menu, there is a new 'move' submenu</li>
          <li>Added these rearrange commands to the shortcuts system, as 'move thumbnails' under the 'thumbnails' set</li>
          <li>The file log arrow button menu now has entries for 'delete already in db' and 'delete everything'</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="560a" date="2024-02-04">
      <url type="details">https://github.com/hydrusnetwork/hydrus/releases/tag/v560a</url>
      <description>
        <p>Hotfix release for the duplicate filter in v560</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="560" date="2024-02-01">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_560</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 560</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The 'edit times' dialog is now available when selecting multiple files</li>
          <li>When the edit times dialog is set to change more than 100 total times, it now verifies with the user that this is correct on dialog ok</li>
          <li>The gallery downloader page 'cog' icon now has a 'do not allow new duplicates' option</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="559" date="2024-01-18">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_559</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 559</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Updated vacuum_timestamps to timestamp_ms and adjusted read/write and the dialog handling to ms</li>
          <li>The file viewing stats manager now tracks 'last viewed time' as ms, and the update pipeline is also updated</li>
          <li>The locations manager now handles all file times in ms, and all the archive/add/delete pipelines are also updated</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="558" date="2024-01-11">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_558</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 558</p>
        <ul>
          <li>We now have rtf support</li>
          <li>ctrl+p and ctrl+n now move the tag listbox selection up and down</li>
          <li>Fixed the 'known urls' menu's open/copy specific urls not appearing when right-clicking any collection. it now shows the front 'display media's' urls</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="557" date="2024-01-04">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_557</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 557</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Optimised large tag filter edit UI</li>
          <li>The cbz scanning tech should now recognise cbzs with four or fewer pages</li>
          <li>Fixed the delete file pre-flight logic</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="556" date="2023-12-14">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_556</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 556</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed, on a file drag and drop, the new export path eliding code from raising an error when the default export phrase would give an empty filename</li>
          <li>Export folders will now fallback to using hash if their normal export filename raises an error</li>
          <li>Holding down ctrl shift while selecting thumbnails now does the same thing as a bare shift and select</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="555" date="2023-12-07">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_555</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 555</p>
        <ul>
          <li>PIL can now load images in int32 or float32 greyscale, with or without ICC Profiles</li>
          <li>The system predicate parser is now plugged into the excellent dateparser library that we already use in downloader parsing</li>
          <li>Fixed some borked page/popup permission checks in the client api</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="554" date="2023-11-30">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_554</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 554</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The 'static check interval' logic is much much simpler</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug in the new static check time code that was stopping certain in-limbo watchers from calculating their correct next check time on program load</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug in the new static check time code that was causing too many checks in long-paused-and-now-unpaused downloaders</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="553" date="2023-11-23">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_553</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 553</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed the false positive "serious I/O Error! This is a significant hard drive problem"</li>
          <li>Fixed some PIL alpha gif rendering on backwards seek and loop</li>
          <li>The file-info-summary lines that appear in the top row thumbnail menu submenu now show if a file has audio/transparency/exif/other metadata/icc profile</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="552a" date="2023-11-16">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_552</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 552</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Menu commands will no longer have their unadjusted label as their tooltip. All tooltips are either the full status bar description or the full label if it was long enough to be elided</li>
          <li>The 'open externally' panel now shows the default filetype thumbnail for formats like zip and epub</li>
          <li>Cleaned up the file/folder move/copy error statements a little more</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="551a" date="2023-11-09">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_551</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 551</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New checkbox under options->thumbnails that disables thumbnail fading</li>
          <li>Fixed the crashes users on PyQt were seeing</li>
          <li>Sped up some random iteration across the program</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="550" date="2023-11-02">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_550</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 550</p>
        <ul>
          <li>If you enter invalid URLs (i.e. non-parsing) into 'manage URLs', the dialog now lets you know they were not apparently good and asks if you want to enter them anyway</li>
          <li>The client now explicitly closes and clears its network connections after five minutes of inactivity</li>
          <li>Optimised deselection of a large number of files when you already have a lot of thumbnails selected</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="549" date="2023-10-26">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_549</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 549</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Optimised taglist sorting code</li>
          <li>Optimised taglist internal update recalc by updating existing items in place instead of remove/replace and skipping cleanup-sort when no new items are added and/or the sort is not count-based</li>
          <li>A new section for potential duplicate search now duplicates the 'do search in idle time' setting you see in the duplicates page and has new 'work packet time' and 'rest time percentage' settings</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="548" date="2023-10-19">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_548</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 548</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Thanks to a user, krita files are now renderable</li>
          <li>Thanks to a user, setting an IPFS 'nocopy' path including your home directory (~) should now expand correctly</li>
          <li>Thanks to a user, the url and hdd downloaders now have 'stop/abort' buttons</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with successive drag and drop file exports that gave different files the same filename</li>
          <li>File filter objects are now serialisable</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
      <release version="547" date="2023-10-12">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_547</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 547</p>
        <ul>
          <li>MPV is less crashy now</li>
          <li>Import support for djvu files</li>
          <li>Cleaned up some filetype parsing code</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="546" date="2023-10-05">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_546</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 546</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed the recent messed up colours in PSD thumbnail generation</li>
          <li>Fixed up some borked button-enabling and status-displaying logic in the file history chart</li>
          <li>Added a checkbox to options->thumbnails to turn off the new blurhash thumbnail fallback</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="545" date="2023-09-28">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_545</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 545</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Thanks to a user's work, hydrus now calculates the blurhash of files with a thumbnail!</li>
          <li>If a file has no thumbnail but does have a blurhash it now presents a thumbnail generated from that blurhash</li>
          <li>The client api version is now 53</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="544" date="2023-09-21">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_544</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 544</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The migrate database dialog now allows you to set a max size</li>
          <li>The 'edit num bytes' widget now supports terabytes (TB)</li>
          <li>Fixed an issue with the recent PSD code updates that was breaking boot for clients running from source without the psd-tools library</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="543" date="2023-09-14">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_543</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 543</p>
        <ul>
          <li>A new string converter rule now allows for extremely easy date parsing, thanks to the dateparser library</li>
          <li>PSD rendering is now much faster and uses less memory</li>
          <li>Description note parsing for the default e621 downloader</li>
          <li>PDF thumbnail generation fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="542" date="2023-09-07">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_542</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 542</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Thanks to a user, we now have pdf thumbnails!</li>
          <li>Newer and better word count for PDFs</li>
          <li>Human-readable file metadata for PDFs</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="541" date="2023-08-31">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_541</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 541</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed the gallery downloader and thread watcher loading with the 'clear highlight' button enabled despite there being nothing currently highlighted</li>
          <li>We now have support for QOI (a png-like lossless image type) and procreate (Apple image project file) files. the former has full support; the latter has thumbnails</li>
          <li>Rewrote the apng parser to work much faster on large files</li>
          <li>Updated the database to hold 'max num bytes' per file storage location</li>
          <li>Reworked the layout of the 'media' options page</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="540" date="2023-08-24">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_540</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 540</p>
        <ul>
          <li>The system predicate parser can now handle 'system:filetype is xxx' for more general human-friendly filetypes like 'video' and 'mkv'</li>
          <li>Fixed many bitmap imports</li>
          <li>If a file has multiple jobs pending, the file maintenance manager now processes all those jobs at once, saving significant disk I/O</li>
          <li>Simplified and cleaned up some of the duplicate system king-fetching code</li>
          <li>Client api version is now 50</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="539" date="2023-08-17">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_539</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 539</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Viewable PSD files</li>
          <li>The program now treats still and animated gifs as separate file types</li>
          <li>Parseable rating predicates</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="538" date="2023-08-10">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_538</url>
      <description>
        <p>Important note on index regeneration</p>
        <ul>
          <li>If you get a note on update about missing indices that need to be regenerated, don't panic!
              Everything is fine, nothing to worry about, let it do its work
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>Changes in Version 538</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New Qt and OpenCV</li>
          <li>Deferred delete system</li>
          <li>HEIF support</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="537" date="2023-08-03">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_537</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 537</p>
        <ul>
          <li>New filetype selector</li>
          <li>Fast database delete</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="536" date="2023-07-26">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_536</url>
      <description>
        <p>Changes in Version 536</p>
        <ul>
          <li>More new filetypes: xcf and gzip filetype</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="535" date="2023-07-19">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_535</url>
    </release>
    <release version="534" date="2023-07-09">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_534</url>
    </release>
    <release version="532" date="2023-06-22">
      <url type="details">https://hydrusnetwork.github.io/hydrus/changelog.html#version_532</url>
    </release>
    <release version="499" date="2022-09-07"/>
    <release version="498" date="2022-08-31"/>
    <release version="497" date="2022-08-24"/>
    <release version="496" date="2022-08-17"/>
    <release version="495" date="2022-08-10"/>
  </releases>
</component>
